

Ve Trinh Lead Engineer at NAB

Birthday: 17 Jan 1987 Mobile: (+84) 907 929 135

Skype: vetrinhtinh

Email: trinhtinhve@gmail.com

Linkedin: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ve-trinh/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/ve-trinh/</a>

Over **10 years** of experience in IT Professional. I'm always trying to finish my tasks effectively, productivity and quality. I am open to learning new things, proactive in my work and try as much as possible to resolve complexity problems. Seeking new challenges in Lead/Senior Engineer.

#### Skill:

- Present in Banking industry (2 years exp) Lead Engineer NodeJs, Postgresql, Graphql, Kafka, AWS, Enterprise, Microservice.
- In the Logistic industry (1 year exp) Senior Backend Engineer Elixir, Functional programming, Phoenix, Postgresql, Elasticsearch.
- In the E-commerce industry (2 years exp) Senior Software Engineer NodeJs, Mongodb, Mysql, AWS, Microservice, Recommendation system.
- In the Outsourcing industry (2 years exp) Project Lead AS3, ReactJs, RoR, Mysql.
- In the Game industry (6 years exp) Junior, Senior, Lead Engineer Java,
  Smartfoxserver, AS3, SQL Realtime game with over 1k CCUs, Game Clustering.

# Others:

NFT game, integrated with blockchain.

#### **Experience:**

- Feb 2021 Present: NAB, Lead Engineer:
  - Lead the team for clarifying requirements from the AU team by engaging stakeholders to have details.
  - Resolve all of the complex issues for the team like streaming data between micro services, implementing the libs to be able to reuse across projects, Data consistency by outbox event pattern and Race condition problems.
  - Understanding components of the enterprise system and how they communicate with each other.
  - Involving the interview process of the company and taking care onboard for new members.
  - Completed Inbound doc project is for handling the upload process of supporting docs from the broker system to bank system.
  - Completed Mini-App Search Application is for searching applications by id, name.

- Completed Broker Aggregator is for handling consolidation data between legacy and new microservices.
- TS, NodeJS, Express, Java, Spring, Postgresql, Kafka, Avro, AWS, Microservice, Graphql.

# • July 2020 - Jan 2021: Yojee, Senior Backend Engineer:

- Learning new technologies quickly with Elixir, Phoenix around 2,3 weeks while implementing new features.
- Understanding the current monolithic system and documenting them.
- Understanding requirements from the Singapore team as well as implementing.
- I got Kudos from my manager in Singapore for finishing the urgent tasks.
- Elixir, Phoenix, Postgresql, Elasticsearch.

# • October 2018 - November 2020: NodeJS Instructor at Nordiccorder:

 To help students to understand the fundamentals of NodeJS: NodeJS/ES6, ExpressJs, Mongodb and how to scale apps.

## • April 2018 - Jun 2020: **ShopBack VN, Senior Software Engineer**:

- Working as a Senior Software Engineer with mainly NodeJS, Microservices and AWS.
- Responsible for developing Restful APIs for Mobile teams with user facing features (mainly features in ShopBack company), high load, high available services and high productivity.
- Building a recommendation system by using PredictionIO and Universal Recommender to give relevant items to users.
- I got a Certificate from the company for resolving and building new features proactively and productily.
- Completed projects: Shopfest, Taobao integration, Rides comparison (Uber, Grab, Comfort, Gojek, Olacabs,...), Recommendation system.
- NodeJs, HDFS, HBase, Spark, Elasticsearch.

#### April 2016 - Mar 2018: Terralogic, Senior Software Engineer - Project Lead:

- Working as a *Project Lead* with mainly ReactJS, Redux, Jest.
- Structure the projects from scratch with ReactJS and Redux.
- Responsible for giving all technical solutions for the team.
- Managing 5 members, and making sure the process of the project is healthy and on schedule.

# April 2016 - August 2016: Socbay, Tech Lead:

- Working as a *Technical Architect* with mainly Java, SmartFoxServer2.x, Unity3D.
- Responsible for the architecture, the code, and the system for the project with a high load of the real time game.
- Responsible for resolving all issues/solutions for the project as well as managing tasks for the team.

- May 2015 Mar 2016: Bach Tuoc So Vietnam, Project Manager, Tech Lead:
  - Working as *Project Manager* and *Tech Lead*.
  - Responsible for managing the project, architecture for code structure and how they communicate with each other for all games.
  - Investigating and applying new technologies for the team.
  - Making sure the process is on schedule and resolving any issues for the team members.
  - Developing a new game server framework for the company with high load and high available. So many games can build on this framework to make the process of developing games faster.
- 2012 May 2015: Bach Tuoc So Vietnam, Team Leader.
- 2011 2012: KingCorp Vietnam, Senior Developer.
- 2010 2011: KingCorp Vietnam, Developer.

#### **Education:**

 Bachelor of Science in Information Technology, HCMC University of Natural Sciences, Vietnam.

# Language:

- Mother Language: Vietnam.
- Other Language: English.